A Finding Aid to the Lillian and Frederick Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003, bulk 1958-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kieslill
Archives of American Art
- Lillian Kiesler papers, circa 1910s-2003; Series 1; (Box 1-39, 47-52, OV 53-55; 41.1 linear feet)
  - Papers of Alice Hodges, circa 1910s-1965; 1.12
    - Printed Material, 1928-1964, undated; 1.12.4
      - Hodges Gardens, 1959-1960, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
        Oversized material housed in Box 51, Folder 2.
      - Postcards, 1928, undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - War Poster, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Exhibition Catalog, Hans Hofmann, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        Oversized material from Box 32, Folder 16.
      - Hodges Garden Brochure, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
        Oversized material from Box 32, Folder 22.
    - Writings, 1923-1960, undated; 1.12.5
      The writings of Alice Hodges include journals, handwritten notes and essays on loose paper, and a manuscript for a children's book, "Great Big Little Horse Tim." Hodges' illustrations for the children's book are located in Artwork, 1938-1980, undated (Sub-subseries 1.12.7). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Journals, 1923-1958, undated (Box 32, Folder 25-26)
      - Letter to the Editor, New York Times, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Writings, 1940-1941, undated (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
      - Writings, "Great Big Little Horse Tim", undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
        See also Box 34, Folder 2.
    - Miscellaneous Files, 1934-1963, undated; 1.12.6
      Found are folders of a variety of subjects, each of which there are few materials. It includes brochures and information about various art schools, correspondence and records from Hodges' involvement in the Committee for Dolia Lorian, various personal items (2 framed photographs, 1 framed drawing, 1 engraved initials stamp, 1 napkin ring, 2 pins), a scrapbook of about Lillian Olinsey's teaching career, printed material and notes from travels to Europe and Mexico, and records from the United States Treasury War Bond Art Auction in 1945. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Art Schools, 1934-1956, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Committee for Dolia Lorian, 1952-1954, undated (Box 33, Folder 6-10)
      - Lawrence Ladd, Research, 1959, undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Personal Items, undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
        7 items housed in shoebox.
      - Scrapbook on Lillian Olinsey Teaching, 1945-1955, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
        Oversized material housed in Box 51, Folder 4.
      - Travels, Europe, 1950, undated (Box 33, Folder 14-16)
      - Travels, Mexico, 1963, undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - United States Treasury War Bond Art Auction, 1945, undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Scrapbook on Lillian Olinsey Teaching, 1945-1955, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
        Oversized material from Box 33, Folder 13.
    - Artwork, 1938-1980, undated; 1.12.7
      Artwork contains original work by Hodges and others, materials related to Hodges' art collection, and an inscribed monograph about Hans Hofmann. Of interest are rolled up drawings and text created by Hodges for a children's book called "Great Big Little Horse Tim" and greeting cards made by Hodges and Lillian Kiesler. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Artwork by Alice Hodges, 1959, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Donated to Provincetown Art Association, 1980, undated (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Drawings and Notes from Others, undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Drawings and Notes from Others, 1951-1954, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - "Great Big Little Horse Tim", undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
        Housed in shoebox; see also Box 33, Folder 4.
      - Greeting Cards by Alice Hodges and Lillian Olinsey Kiesler, undated (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
      - Hodges Art Collection, 1938-1963, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Monograph, Hans Hofmann, circa 1965 (Box 34, Folder 6)
        Oversized material housed in Box 51, Folder 3; Inscribed by Hofmann.
      - Sketches and Sketchbook, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Hans Hofmann, circa 1965 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        Oversized material from Box 34, Folder 6; Inscribed by Hofmann.
    - Photographic Material, circa 1910s-1950s; 1.12.8
      Personal photographs of travel, family and friends are the primary materials found here. There are 31 rolled negative strips in metal canisters of Frederick Kiesler sculptures, Provincetown and Hans Hofmann, Wellfleet, Empire State Music Festival (1955), and travels to Colorado and Europe. Some of the negatives may be printed and found in this sub-subseries or in Photographic Material, circa 1920s-2000 (Subseries 1.13) in Series 1. Negatives are labeled either on the canister or on the paper wrapper around the negatives. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
      - Personal, circa 1910s-1950s (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Reproductions of Artwork, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Travel, 1934-1950, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Slides, Travel, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Rolled Negative Strips of Artwork, Travel, Hans Hofmann, and Miscellaneous, 1941-1955, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
        See also Box 47.
      - Camera Lens Filters, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Rolled Negative Strips of Artwork, Travel, Hans Hofmann, and Miscellaneous, 1941-1955, undated (Box 47)
        Items from Box 34, Folder 12; 31 items.
      - Camera Lens Filters, undated (Box 47)
        Items from Box 34, Folder 13; 5 items.
  - Photographic Material, circa 1920s-2000, undated; 1.13
    This subseries contains photographs and negatives spanning most of Lillian Kiesler's life. Photographs are mostly black and white and color snapshots of her friends and family at events and at home. Also found are candid photos of Hans Hofmann, Alice Hodges, Frederick Kiesler, and Alcopley. Photographs are filed first with folders arranged alphabetically by subject. Followed are other types of photographic material arranged alphabetically.
    - Artwork, "Kiesler and Wife" by Will Barnet, circa 1963-1965 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Artwork, Frederick Kiesler, Damaged, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Artwork, Lillian Kiesler, 1981, 1990, undated (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Artwork, Others, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Events (Box 34)
      - Frederick Kiesler Exhibition, Andre Emmerlich Gallery, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 18)
      - Frederick Kiesler Exhibition, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 19)
      - Frederick Kiesler Reception, Gotham Bookmart (contact sheets), 1966 (Box 34, Folder 20)
      - Frederick Kiesler Retrospective, Museum Moderner Kunst, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 21)
      - Inside the Endless House Publication Party, circa 1967 (Box 34, Folder 22)
      - John Little Funeral, Green River Cemetery, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 23)
      - Lillian Kiesler Lecture at Cooper Union, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Events (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous Events, Openings, and Functions, 1958, circa 1960s (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous Events, Openings, and Functions, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Events, Openings, and Functions, 1990s (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Family and Friends (Box 35)
      - Al Copely, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Andres, Jo, and Steve and Lucian Buscemi, 1988-2000, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Charlton, Maryette, circa 1927-1994, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Charlton, Maryette, Greeting Cards, 1969-1994, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Charlton, Shannon B. (Etna Barr), 1965, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Godchildren of Lillian Kiesler, 1972-2000, undated (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
      - Hodges, Alice, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Hofmann, Hans, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 35, Folder 12)
        See also Box 30, Folders 18-19.
      - Scott, undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Weiler, Max, 1990-1993, undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Winslow, Kirk, 1972-1993, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Family and Friends, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
    - Family and Friends, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 18-23)
    - Family and Friends, 1941 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Family and Friends, circa 1950s (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Family and Friends, circa 1960s (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Family and Friends, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Family and Friends, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Family and Friends, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Family and Friends, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Family and Friends, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 31-35)
    - Family and Friends, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Family and Friends, 1980-1981 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Family and Friends, 1980-1983 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Family and Friends, 1983-1985 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Family and Friends, 1990s (Box 36, Folder 6-16)
    - Family and Friends, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Family and Friends, undated (Box 36, Folder 18-19)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, 1926-1965, undated (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, "1750 House" and "Sunshine" (with Alice Hodges), circa 1930s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, Buildings, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, Furniture (at home of Ron Warren), 1995 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, Sculptures, 1981, undated (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, Storage, 1968, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, Yale School of Art and Architecture, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, circa 1940s-2000 (Box 36, Folder 27-28)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, Hands, circa 1930s (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, Performances, 1978-1994, undated (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, Portraits, 1930s-2000 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
    - Kiesler, Lillian and Maryette Charlton, 1979-2001, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Kiesler, Lillian and Students, circa 1944, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 52, Folder 3.
    - Miscellaneous, 1930s, 1960s, 1975, 1993, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Oversized material housed in Box 52, Folder 2.
    - Miscellaneous Contact Photos, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Photographs by Paula Court, 1993-1998 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Places, Japan, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Places, New York City, 1987-1999, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Places, Schooley's Mountain, 1968-1999, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Places, Unidentified, undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Album, undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Oversized material housed in Box 52, Folder 1.
    - Negatives, Family and Friends, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Negatives, Family and Friends, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Negatives, Family and Friends, 1941 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Negatives, Frederick Kiesler Exhibition, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Negatives, Unidentified, undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Slides, undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Tintypes, 1939, undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Album, Cataloging of Johnson Estate, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 37, Folder 12.
    - Miscellaneous, 1983, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 37, Folder 5.
    - 14 matted and signed photos of Lillian Kiesler with Students of Woodward School Outdoor's "Ketching Trip," photos by Nancy Clements, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 37, Folder 4.
  - Sound and Video Recordings, 1978-2001, undated; 1.14
    Sound and video recordings include recordings of productions in which Lillian Kiesler performed, and music, film, or live stage performances written, directed, or performed by friends. Recordings are on 2 sound discs (vinyl), 32 sound cassettes, 3 sound tape reels, 3 sound discs (CD), and 17 videocassettes (VHS). Folders are arranged by format, then alphabetically by subject.
    - "Paul's Boutique" and "Polly Wog Stew," Beastie Boys, 1982, 1989; 2 Sound discs (vinyl) (Box 37, Folder 20)
      Inscribed sleeve, Michael Diamond. Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 6.
    - Sound Cassettes, (Housed in shoebox) (Box 37, Folder 21)
      - "Amor Elusive Empty August," Lucia Dlugoszewski, 1980; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "Arts Forum," Maryette Charlton and Lillian Kiesler interviewed by John Hagan, 1978; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Astrologist Reading, 1992; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
        See also Box 2, Folder 3.
      - "Beastie Boys Anthology: The Sounds of Science," Cassettes 1 and 2, 1999; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "Beautiful Bird Sounds" from "The Hinger," Rebecca Moore, 1994; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
        See also Box 12, Folder 17.
      - "Burgess and Jonathan Meredith: Us Too!", undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Interview with Maryette Charlton, Lillian Kiesler and Jane Smith conducted by Carole Laidlow, 1990; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "Dance," Hillary Easton, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "Dreaming Out Loud," Jo Andres, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
        See also Box 12, Folder 15.
      - "Get a Life", 1994; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Jay Gottlieb, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Jay Gottlieb Russian Recital, MOMA Paris, 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Kiesler (side 1) and Elliot (side 2), undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Lillian Kiesler Reads Poems of Frederick Kiesler, 1996; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "On Theater," Lillian Kiesler and Maryette Charlton, 1994; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - "Pierce Sever," Lucia Dlugoszewski, 1980; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Reading of James Purdy's "Green Knowledge," and "Mozo Lobo", 1986; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
      - Diane Thome, 1984; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 37)
    - Readings with Joel Thome, 1979-1989; 10 Sound cassettes (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Unlabeled Tapes, Henry Cowell (1996) and piano music, 1996, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "Admiral Charcoal's Song" by Rebecca Moore, 1995; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "Code One: Fourteen Parts," Cindy Lubar Bishop and Peter Girard, 2000; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Hello Nasty" by Beastie Boys, 1998; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "Anais" by Diane Thome, undated; 1 sound tape reels (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Lucia Dlugoszewsky, undated; 1 sound tape reels (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Sunflower" by Diane Thome, 1979; 1 sound tape reels (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "The Afterglow: A Tribute to Robert Frost" from Burgess Meredith, undated; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "Black Kites" directed by Jo Andres, undated; 2 videocassettes: VHS (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "The Dancer Revealed" by Martha Graham, 1994; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Dances by Hilary Easton, 1991; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "Documentation of Some Installations," Judith Barry, 2001; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "Hans Hofmann, Reflections by Former Students", undated; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "In Memoriam: Leone A. Elliott," The University of Iowa Museum of Art, 1996; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Kiesler Prize footage from Ken Saylor, Vienna, 2000; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 3)
      See also Box 13, Folder 18 and Box 20, Folder 6.
    - "Letters from Hans Hofmann: A Reading by Lillian Kiesler," and "Ancestors" by Jo Andres, 1993; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 4)
      See also Box 29, Folders 12-13.
    - M. Schmidt Live Shoot, "The Promiscuity of Time" and "Dances," Jo Andres, 1989; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Martha Graham" by Agnes de Mille, 1999; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 6)
      See also Box 12, Folder 19.
    - Millennium Monument World Peace Bell, 1998; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 7)
      See also Box 14, Folder 2.
    - "The Three Muses" Lillian Kiesler, Jane Smith, and Maryette Charlton Reading Gertrude Stein's 'The Making of Americans", 1990; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Toshiko Takaezu: at Home," Hunterdon Museum of Art, 1998; 1 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - The University of Iowa Museum of Art 25th Anniversary Celebration, Tapes 1 and 2, 1994; 2 videocassettes: VHS (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Oversized sound recordings from Box 37, 1982, 1989; 2 Sound discs (Box 50, Folder 6)
- Frederick Kiesler papers, 1923-1992; Series 2; 7.1 Linear feet Boxes 40-46, OV 53
  Series 2 contains Frederick Kiesler's papers and documents his professional career as an architect, sculptor, and teacher. Among his papers are biographical materials, including passports, schedule and appointment books; correspondence with architects, publishers, editors, universities, museums, galleries, manufacturers, artists and friends, including L. Alcopley, Leopold Arnaud, Armand P. Bartos, Piero and Virginia Dorazio, George Howe, Kay Johnson, Jane Owen, and others, and photocopied letters from Katherine Dreier, Marcel Duchamp, and Piet Mondrian; business and finance records, most of which were collected in preparing tax returns; correspondence and materials related to exhibitions, including "Inside the Endless House" (1966) and the International Theatre Exposition (1924); teaching files and production notes from Juilliard School of Music; personal notes and writings; a bound copy of the "Bibliography of Works Written By or About Frederick Kiesler"; clippings, and other printed materials; and several photographs of artwork.
  There is overlap between this series and Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, circa 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1), especially exhibition files, printed material, and photographs.
  The series is arranged as 8 subseries:
  2.1: Biographical Material, 1947-1965, undated
  2.2: Correspondence, 1923-1965, undated
  2.3: Business and Financial Records, 1937-1965
  2.4: Exhibition Files, 1924-1992, undated
  2.5: Teaching Files, 1937-1964, undated
  2.6: Writings and Notes, 1933-1980, undated
  2.7: Printed Material, 1926-1966, undated
  2.8: Photographic Material, undated
  - Biographical Material, 1947-1965, undated; 2.1
    Biographical material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Appointments and Schedules, 1965, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Passports, 1947, 1953, 1957, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Schedule Books, 1964-1965 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Schedule Book, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1965, undated; 2.2
    The bulk of Frederick Kiesler's correspondence is with architects, publishers, editors, universities, museums, galleries, manufacturers, artists and friends about projects, business, and teaching; personal correspondence does not comprise a significant portion of the material until after 1952. Correspondence includes incoming letters and carbon copies of letters from Frederick Kiesler; there is some correspondence in German and French. Included are L. Alcopley, Leopold Arnaud, Armand P. Bartos, Piero and Virginia Dorazio, George Howe, Kay Johnson, Jane Owen, and others. There are also photocopied letters from Katherine Dreier, Marcel Duchamp, and Piet Mondrian. There is no correspondence to or from Lillian Kiesler found here. Additional related correspondence is in Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, circa 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). Correspondence is arranged first by subject, then chronologically.
    - Christmas Cards Received, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Office of War Information Exhibition, 1944-1945 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Chronological, 1923, 1926, 1930-1932 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Chronological, 1933-1936 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Chronological, 1937 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Chronological, 1938-1939 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Chronological, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Chronological, 1941 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Chronological, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Chronological, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Chronological, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Chronological, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Chronological, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Chronological, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Chronological, 1949 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Chronological, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Chronological, 1951-1952 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Chronological, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Chronological, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Chronological, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Chronological, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Chronological, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Chronological, January-June 1958 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Chronological, July-December 1958 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Chronological, January-March 1959 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Chronological, April-May 1959 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Chronological, June-July 1959 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Chronological, August-September 1959 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Chronological, October-December 1959 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Chronological, January-March 1960 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Chronological, April-May 1960 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Chronological, June-July 1960 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Chronological, August-December 1960 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Chronological, January-June 1961 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Chronological, July-December 1961 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Chronological, January-March 1962 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Chronological, April-May 1962 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Chronological, June-August 1962 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Chronological, September-December 1962 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Chronological, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Chronological, January-June 1964 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Chronological, July-December 1964 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Chronological, January-March 1965 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Chronological, April-June 1965 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Chronological, July-August 1965 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Chronological, September-December 1965 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Chronological, undated (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Business and Financial Records, 1937-1965; 2.3
    The bulk of the materials found here are tax returns from the 1940s to mid-1960s and records used in preparing returns, such as bank statements, bills and receipts, and income memos. Also included are travel documents and expenses, inquiries and notes about job applicants, and material related to a Ford Foundation grant. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Bank Receipts, Steffi Kiesler, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Bank Records, 1959-1961 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Bills Paid, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 3-15)
    - Bills Paid, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 16-19)
    - Harry Bodansky Income Tax Data, 1953-1962 (Box 42, Folder 20-24)
    - Cancelled Checks and Bills, Steffi Kiesler, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 25-26)
    - Chemical Bank N.Y. Trust Co., 1962 (Box 42, Folder 27-38)
    - Chemical Bank N.Y. Trust Co., Deposits, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    - Domestic Travel, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 40)
    - Expenses, Petty Cash, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 41-42)
    - Expenses, Petty Cash, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 43)
    - Federation Bank and Trust Co., 1963 (Box 42, Folder 44)
    - Federation Bank and Trust Co., Deposits, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Federation Bank and Trust Co., Regular Checking, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Federation Bank and Trust Co., Special Account Checking, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Financial, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation Bills, 1962-1964 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation Bills, 1st and 2nd Installments, 1962-1963 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation Bills Paid, 3rd Installment, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation Guggenheim Grant, 1962-1965 (Box 43, Folder 8)